PUJAN SHRESTHA

208-240-5956| pujan.shrestha@ttu.edu|LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pujansresta/1002 Frankford Ave, Lubbock, TX, 79416

Website: <u>www.pujanshrestha.com</u>

INTRODUCTION

Prospective Data Analyst with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insights via data analytics and advanced data-driven methods. Experienced at creating data regression models, using predictive data modeling, and analyzing data mining algorithms to deliver insights and solutions to complex business problems

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University, Rawls College of Business: GPA 3.50/4.0 Bachelor of Business Administration, Information Technology **Richland College, Dallas County Community College:** GPA 3.92/4.0 Associate of Science

Dallas, TexasGraduation: December 2018

Graduation: December 2020

Lubbock, Texas

Relevant Coursework: Database Management System, Systems Design, Emerging Technology, Business Statistics, System Security, Business Computer Application, System Analysis, Information Systems Project Management, Operation Management

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Programming: Proficient in R, Python & MySQL
- IDE: R-Studio, PyCharm, Jupiter, MYSQL Workbench
- Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Matplotlib, ggplot
- Web Scraping: Scrapy, URLLIB, Pandas
- Machine Learning: Classification, Reinforcement
- Data Analysis: Data Wrangling, EDA

PROJECT (www.pujanshrestha.com)

- R Programming: Soccer Trends
- MySQL: Manipulation

- **Python:** Verification
- Machine Learning: Facial Recognition

CERTIFICATION

- TABLEAU: Desktop Certified Associate
- W3: Certified SQL Developer

- MICROSOFT: Certified Microsoft Office Excel Specialist
- COMPTIA: Certified CompTIA IT Fundamentals

EXPERIENCE

Texas Tech University, Hospitality

Lubbock, Texas

Student Manager, Stangel Hall:

September 2018 - December 2020

- Managed and coordinated hundreds of clients in an organized manner to prevent any delay and obstacles to timely and seamless service delivery
- Performed training and workshop for trainees (20+) leading to better team foundation for the year 2018/2019

LEADERSHIP

Rawls Student Council

May 2019 - Present

- Gather feedback from students and work closely with Dean on issue's student has in the Rawls College of Business, TTU
- Encourage communication between students, faculty and the administration and contribute in projects and data recording using Excel

Leo Club Kathmandu, Nepal

October 2015 – August 2016

 Presented and implemented New Database and Order System (Focused more on Simplicity and User Friendly) for Clubs Membership track

HONOR & AWARDS

Texas Tech University: Scholarship and Financial Aid

August 2018

Earned Proven Achiever Transfer Scholarship: \$13000 at Texas Tech University (Highest Transfer Scholarship)

Phi Theta Kappa/ Texas Region/ Alpha Alpha Xi Chapter

February 2018

Achieved 3.5+ GPA during Sophomore & Junior year, gaining admittance to scholastic honor society

Leo Club Kathmandu, Nepal: General Member and IT guidance

January 2016

• Awarded 100% Attendance & Responsible Personal Award, 2015-2016